[Music]
hello welcome to this session I'm B
Knutsen I'm and I'm going to talk about
what's new in Warehouse posting and
entries we'll briefly touch upon how it
works until now and then how it will
work from now on and what you need to be
care of you as a partner or developer so
the way Warehouse working I'm other
ledgers is that only one user can post
at the time and you usually have a
register like a warehouse register and
then some entries and since only one
user at the time can post these entries
will come in consecutive to
order and the warehouse register then
knows that it owns from entry number A
to
B and a brief look at code doesn't look
exactly like this but something like
this is that when we create new
entries we do a lock
table and then we do a find last to find
the last entry and then we increment
that entry number and then we continue
that to increment and assign that to the
new entries and then we insert most of
you should be familiar with this and
similarly if we do a drill down from the
register you can see that we do a simple
set range on the entry number with the
warehouse registers from and to in
number so this is how it works today or
until
now in
bc25 we will allow multiple users at the
same time to post and we'll do that by
using number sequences as you can see in
the example here which is an elaboration
from before that there's some mix
between green and blue entries and the
red and green
entries and the way the code looks now
conceptually is that we get the next
entry number from a function which
basically just calls to a number
sequence and then gives you the next
number we also need to inform the
warehouse entry to
which uh register it belongs
to so there's also a new field for
warehouse register that we we get from
the register number and finally instead
of just insert Ing we call a new
function that we call insert
record and that's because maybe someone
else has posted old style with a lock
table um find last and so on so what we
do there is we try to insert and if that
doesn't succeed we need to reset the
number
sequence but otherwise it's business as
usual the last thing you notice here is
that we also have a sift bucket number
that we assign to a semi- random number
between zero and four because what many
people don't know is that if you have a
combination of values in a sift index
for instance item number and
location and two users insert Warehouse
entries to the same item and location at
the same time they will lock each
other due to the index
so by adding this um extra sift bucket
number we will avoid that or at least
reduce the risk on the drill down just
as before except that We additionally
filter on the register number so either
it's zero because it's from before 25 or
it is the reg number we did this to
avoid expensive upgrades and finally why
do you care well you care if you work on
Warehouse entries and you have an
extension or an app that creates entries
or relies on the way we assign numbers
for instance we have an event that's
called on in it something that we call
after we have initiated the warehous
entry but before we insert it and for
instance you can see we pass on the
current counter the entry number and we
also pass on the warehouse regone so I
suspect somebody uses it
to insert extra Warehouse
entries um and if you do then you might
want to implement the same as we have
done if for whatever reason it doesn't
work for you you can go to the feature
keys and disable this function so there
is a feature key that we have enabled by
default but you can turn it off and in
the code there is a function in the
warehouse setup that allows you to read
it easily so you can you can see what
we've done here and that's basically it
um thank you so I I'll stop here with
the new recipe or new pattern to
implement thank you